[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
So, we now built a whole new kind of restaurant experience, or
因此现在我们要一起参与一个全新的餐馆经历 或者说是
restaurant review experience, using classifiers.
餐馆评价的例子 利用分类器的方法
Let's dig in and really understand a little bit more what a classifier is,
让我们继续深入理解一些这是一个什么样子的分类器
and some other applications of classification.
这个分类器可以有什么其他的应用
So a classifier takes some input x, for example a sentence from the review or
这个分类器获取一些输入值x 例如 本例中的一个句子 或者
other inputs as we'll see.
其他我们之后会提到的输入
It pushes it through what's called a model to output some value y,
把这个输入值放进我们称之为“模型”的东西 然后会有一个输出值y
that we're trying to predict.
这个输出值y就是我们要预测的数值
And here it's a class, for example, positive or negative.
这里涉及到一个分类问题 例如 正类或负类
So positive in the case of sentiment analysis corresponds with thumbs up
在这个情感分析的例子中 正类就是“竖起大拇指”的好评
reviews, while negative corresponds with thumbs down.
而负类就是“大拇指朝下”的差评
But this is just one example of classification.
但是这只是其中的一个分类器的例子
You can look at text, for example, a web page, I want
你可以推广到其他文字类的分类应用 例如 一个网页 我想要
to figure out which webpages interest me, and I can align them to categories.
找出那些页面可能引起我的兴趣 我就可以通过分类来实现
For example, is this about education, a page about education,
例如 这个是关于教育的吗？是不是一个关于教育的网页
is it a page about finance, is it a page about technology and so on?
这个网页是关于金融的吗？是关于科技的吗？等等
So, there's not just two categories.
这个例子里就不只是有两个类别了
There can be three, four, or
可以有三个 四个
even thousands of categories I'm predicting from.
甚至是我要预测的是上千个类别
Now, another example of classification,
现在 再举一另一个分类的例子
which really has impacted all of our lives, is in spam filtering.
这个与我们的生活息息相关的分类的例子，就是垃圾邮件过滤了
Some of you might remember, perhaps in the early 2000s, what spam filters were like.
或许你们之中还有记得 在20世纪初的时候 垃圾邮件过滤器是什么样的
The quality was not very good.
那时的垃圾邮件过滤器的质量是非常差的
Really, they were all hand-tuned things where somebody said,
事实上 他们都是手工设计的特征 如果邮件中含有某些人，
oh it has certain words, it must be spam.
或者包含某些特定字眼 就判定为垃圾邮件
But the spammers kept changing the words a little bit,
但是垃圾邮件制作者一直在试图改变邮件的文字
adding numbers instead of letters, and beating the spam filters.
将单词替换成数字 来逃过过滤器的过滤
And what really changed the world of spam filtering.
是什么技术真正地改变了垃圾邮件过滤？
It changed it so much that I don't even look at my spam folder, actually, sorry if
机器学习 他带来的改变如此之大 以至于我甚至都不需要看我的垃圾邮件目录
your message went to my spam folder, I just don't open it, is machine learning.
如果你的邮件不慎进入我的垃圾邮件目录 那么非常抱歉 我不会打开
It's classifiers.
这就是分类器
They took the input x of the email and
他们把邮件作为输入x
they fed it through a classifier that predicted whether it's spam or not.
把输入送入分类器 然后预测是否是垃圾邮件
It did that really well.
这个分类器在处理垃圾邮件时非常奏效
And it does it by not just looking at the text of the email, but
他不仅仅是看邮件的文字
it looks at other characteristics.
还会考虑其他特征
So for example, who sent it.
比如说 谁发送的邮件
If it somebody's whose a close friend, or somebody you have lots of vacation,
是和你非常亲密的朋友 或者和你一起有度过很多闲暇时光的人
with it's less likely to be spam.
这些人发的邮件不太可能是垃圾邮件
The IP address is a person sending from the usual computer and so on.
邮件发送者的IP地址 是不是来自常用电脑 等等
Lots of information.
有太多的信息可以用来判定
So this is another really interesting practical application.
这就是另一个特别有趣并且实用的例子
In computer vision, we do a lot of classification.
在计算机视觉领域 我们做了很多的分类
We'll take an image, and figure out what is in that image.
我们输入一副图片 然后识别出图片中的内容
For example, here, the input x are the pixels of the image.
举个例子 这里的输入x是图像的像素点
We feed it to a classifier, and
我们把这个输入送入分类器 然后
we're going to predict things like is this a dog?
我们会预测这个图里的是一只狗吗？
In fact it's a Labrador Retriever, Golden Retriever, or a different kind of dog.
实际上，这是一只拉布拉多猎犬，金毛猎犬，还是其他种类的狗呢？
This is actually my dog, Labrador Retriever.
这个实际上是我的狗 一只拉布拉多猎犬
And as we will see later on in the deep learning module,
我们在之后的“深度学习”课程部分，将会继续讨论这个例子
there's really interesting new ways of doing this with very high accuracy.
这里确实有一个十分有趣的新方法，可以很高准确率地实现这样的分类
Now you can also use classification in medical diagnosis systems, and
你也可以将分类器应用到医疗诊断中去
in fact this is what your doctor does.
事实上 这就是你的医生干的事情
They take your temperature, maybe they look at your x-ray, they look at some
获取你的体温信息，或许是查看你的X光片，或者其他的医疗检测结果
medical tests and they try to make a prediction about what's ailing somebody.
然后预测你的身体状况
Maybe they say nah, nah, you're just healthy, or you have a cold,
你是非常健康的 或者是着凉了？
you have the flu, maybe even you have pneumonia.
患了流感？甚至可以预测你是否患了急性肺炎
That's a variable y that's being predicted,
预测的结果可以用变量y来表示
what is the disease that's going on.
表示现在患者疾病
Now these days, there's really interesting new things around personalized medicine,
最近 关于个人医疗的问题出现了很多新东西
because the prediction doesn't just depend on the standard measurements, but
因为现在的医疗诊断不仅仅是基于传统的检测
can be really personalized for me.
还要进行个性化的诊断
Can depend on my particular DNA sequencing, which is pretty exciting and
可以根据特定的DNA序列来进行诊断，无疑是一种有趣并且
also my lifestyle, which maybe look something like
是一种生活方式 很多类似这样的东西
or maybe more realistic, something like this.
或者是比这个例子更实用的
And so, given all these measurements,
给定了上述的这些检测方法
can make an even better prediction at what's ailing me.
就可以更好的对我现在的身体状况进行判断
Now this idea of classification in off-machine learning,
当然现在的一些机器学习中的分类方法
has really gone much further, even to be able to read your mind.
已经越来越深入 甚至可以读懂你的大脑
So when I was at Carnegie-Mellon, Tom Mitchell, one of my friends and colleagues
我去卡内基梅隆时，我的一个叫 ToM Mitchell 的朋友
at his office next door, and he come to me and says, we've done this amazing thing.
和他旁边办公室的同事，和我讲述了一个特别令人惊异的事情
Which would take an image of your brain using a technology called FMRI,
我们通过一种叫FMRI的技术，获得你大脑的影像
which is brain scan, and predict when you're reading a word of text,
扫描你的大脑，预测你现在正在阅读的是什么文字
whether you're reading the word hammer or the word house.
你是在读“Hammer"（锤子）这个单词呢，还是”House"（房子）?
So it's really reading your mind.
这个分类器读懂了你的大脑
But in fact, he went on to do many interesting things.
当然 还可以继续做一些其他有趣的事情
For example, if you're looking at a picture of a hammer or a house, but
比如，你是在看一副锤子的照片，还是一个房子的照片
you train the classified on them you reading words hammers and house,
训练分类器时 用的是你正在阅读“Hammer”（锤子）和"House"（房子）的单词来训练的
you're still able to read your mind and figure out what picture you're looking at.
这样训练仍然可以读懂你的大脑 知道你现在是在看锤子还是房子的照片
So this is yet
恩，这就是现在
the next frontier of classification to understand how the brain works.
下一代分类器的目标 读懂你的大脑
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community